Guide to the United Student Christian Council Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Related Organizations, Series IX
  - Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions
    - Publications and Printed Materials
      - Galley proof, Called in Revolution: Perspective on Ecumenical Mission by Bruce Morgan, 1956 (Box 118, Folder 1387)
      - Leaflets, Careers in the Christian Mission no. 1-7: The Agricultural Missionary, The Educational Missionary, The Medical Missionary, The Missionary Nurse, The Missionary Social Worker, The Minister in Missions, and Working Abroad as a Christian, circa 1952 (Box 119, Folder 1388)
      - Newsletter, Christian Horizons: Openings in Missionary Service, 1947-1948, 1950-1959 (Box 119, Folder 1389)
      - Newsletter, No Retreat: a Student Volunteer Movement Quarterly for China-Mission-Minded Students, January 1946 (Box 119, Folder 1390)
      - Newsletter, SVM Newsletter, 1949-1959 (Box 119, Folder 1391)
      - Pamphlets, Know Your SVM, Letters of a Modern Mystic, The Missionary Wife, and What is a Missionary?, 1937, 1956, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1392)
      - Plays, Where Hope is Born: a Play on Student Relief by Hilda Benson and Straight Furrow: a Three Act Play on China by Hilda Benson and Elizabeth Howell (Box 119, Folder 1393)
      - SVM declaration cards, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1394)
  - University Christian Mission
    - Articles re. University Christian Mission, 1947, 1949, 1950, 1952, 1955 (Box 119, Folder 1395)
    - Correspondence, General, 1945-1947 (Box 119, Folder 1396)
    - Correspondence, General, 1947-1948 (Box 119, Folder 1397)
    - Correspondence, General, 1948-1949 (Box 119, Folder 1398)
    - Correspondence, General some re. publication on the guide on evangelism, 1949-1950 (Box 119, Folder 1399)
    - Correspondence, General, 1950-1951 (Box 119, Folder 1400)
    - Correspondence, General, 1951-1952 (Box 119, Folder 1401)
    - Correspondence, General, 1952-1954 (Box 119, Folder 1402)
    - Correspondence, General, 1954-1958 (Box 119, Folder 1403)
    - Meeting agendas and documents, 1947, 1953, 1954, 1957 (Box 120, Folder 1404)
    - Meeting agendas and documents, 1958 (Box 120, Folder 1405)
    - Memos, 1946, 1949, 1954-1956, 1958 (Box 120, Folder 1406)
    - Minutes, 1943-1947 (Box 120, Folder 1407)
    - Minutes, 1947-1949 (Box 120, Folder 1408)
    - Minutes, 1949-1953 (Box 120, Folder 1409)
    - Minutes, 1954-1959 (Box 120, Folder 1410)
    - Printed materials, Booklets, How to Plan, Conduct, and Follow-Up a Religious Emphasis Week and Religion in Life Week: a Guide by James L. Stoner, 1953, 1956 (Box 120, Folder 1411)
    - Printed materials, Brochures and flyers, circa 1947-1957 (Box 120, Folder 1412)
    - Printed materials, Newsletter, University Christian Mission News, 1953, 1955 (Box 120, Folder 1413)
    - Printed materials, News releases for individuals participating in religious emphasis weeks, 1947-1948 (Box 120, Folder 1414)
    - Printed materials, Pamphlets, The University Christian Mission Manual, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1415)
    - Printed materials, Paper, Student Evangelism: a Guide for Study and Discussion on College and University Campuses, 1951 (Box 120, Folder 1416)
    - Printed materials, University Christian Mission Work-book for Directors of Missions and Members of the Executive, Program, and Campus Committees (Box 120, Folder 1417)
    - Reports, Annual reports of the UCM, 1948-1949, 1952-1953, 1954-1955 (Box 121, Folder 1418)
    - Reports, Campus reports, 1946 (Box 121, Folder 1419)
    - Reports, Miscellaneous, 1951-1958 (Box 121, Folder 1420)
    - Schedule of missions, 1946-1957 (Box 121, Folder 1421)
    - Year of evangelism information, 1948 (Box 121, Folder 1422)
  - World Student Service Fund
    - General Records
      - Committee of Ten, 1952 (Box 121, Folder 1423)
      - Correspondence, General, 1945-1947 (Box 121, Folder 1424)
      - Correspondence, re. Displaced persons include reports and newspaper clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 121, Folder 1425)
      - Correspondence, General, 1948-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1426)
      - Correspondence, re. Displaced persons includes reports, 1949-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1427)
      - Correspondence, re. Displaced persons, 1950-1951 (Box 121, Folder 1428)
      - Correspondence, General, 1950-1951 (Box 121, Folder 1429)
      - Correspondence, General, 1952 (Box 122, Folder 1430)
      - Financial papers, 1951-1952 (Box 122, Folder 1431)
      - International student service conference, 1949 (Box 122, Folder 1432)
      - Minutes, 1945-1947 (Box 122, Folder 1433)
      - Minutes, 1948-1949 (Box 122, Folder 1434)
      - Minutes, 1949-1950 (Box 122, Folder 1435)
      - Minutes, 1951-1952 (Box 122, Folder 1436)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-19461952 (Box 123, Folder 1437)
      - National Student Relief Committee, 1941-1943 (Box 123, Folder 1438)
      - Papers re. student relief, 1947-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1439)
      - Personnel Committee, 1951 (Box 123, Folder 1440)
      - Photographs, Project in Chungking, Shanghai, and Chungtu (Box 123, Folder 1441)
      - Reports, Financial, 1945-1947 (Box 123, Folder 1442)
      - Reports, Financial, 1947-1948 (Box 123, Folder 1443)
      - Reports, Financial, 1949 (Box 123, Folder 1444)
      - Reports, Financial, 1950 (Box 123, Folder 1445)
      - Reports, Staff Report on China and Report of WSSF to USCC annual meeting, 1947, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1446)
      - World student relief and reconstruction, 1945-1948 (Box 123, Folder 1447)
    - Publications and Printed Materials
      - Booklets re. displaced students including It's Your Chance to Give Them a Chance and Program of Mutual Assistance for Universities, College, and Preparatory Schools 1951-1952, circa 1944-1952 (Box 123, Folder 1448)
      - Booklets, WSSF Handbook: 1941-1942 Campaign, Road to Recovery: Campaign Manual 1947-1948, WSSF Campaign Manual, 1941, 1947, n.d. (Box 123, Folder #1449)
      - Brochures and leaflets, circa 1944-1952 (Box 124, Folder 1450)
      - Newsletter, European Student Relief Fund, 1942-1945 (Box 124, Folder 1451)
      - Newsletter, NRSC News-Letter (National Student Relief Committee located in Chungking, China), 1941-1943 (Box 124, Folder 1452)
      - Newsletter, WSSF: Middle Atlantic & New York Region, 1951, 1952 (Box 124, Folder 1453)
      - Newsletter, WSSF News, 1941-1943, 1946, 1948-1953 (Box 124, Folder 1454)
      - News releases, 1950, 1952 (Box 124, Folder 1455)
      - Pamphlets, Design for Peace: The Story of World Student Relief 1937-1946, The First World War and Student Relief by Anne Wiggin, Out of the Ruins: Fifth Report on Student Relief Activities April 1945-March 1946, Road to Recovery: Information for Canvassers (Questions and Answers), Students in Europe Must Life: a First Report on War Relief April1940-March 1941, and Student Relief in China 1937-1940, 1940, 1941, 1946, and n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1456)
      - Papers and a play, "A Guide to WSSF-WUS Program of Relief and International Education in Europe," preparatory work paper for the WSSF consultation on "The Role of American Universities in World Universities Service," and Where Hope is Born: a Play on Student Relief by Hilda Benson, 1950, 1951, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1457)
  - World University Service (formerly International Student Service)
    - World University Service International Geneva Headquarters
      - Circular letters, International Student Service, 1949-1950 (Box 124, Folder 1458)
      - Circular letters, International Student Service, 1950 (Box 124, Folder 1459)
      - Circular letters, re. dissolution of World Student Relief organization, 1950-1951 (Box 124, Folder 1460)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1951-1952 (Box 125, Folder 1461)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1951-1952 (Box 125, Folder 1462)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1953 (Box 125, Folder 1463)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1956-1957 (Box 125, Folder 1464)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1957 (Box 125, Folder 1465)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1957 (Box 125, Folder 1466)
      - Circular letters, World University Service, 1958-1959 (Box 125, Folder 1467)
      - Correspondence, re. International Student Service and the American scene, 1947 (Box 125, Folder 1468)
      - Correspondence, re. Personnel issues, 1950-1951 (Box 125, Folder 1469)
      - Correspondence, re. Personnel issues, 1951-1952 (Box 125, Folder 1470)
      - Correspondence, Personnel Committee, 1952 (Box 125, Folder 1471)
      - Correspondence, Personnel Committee, 1952 (Box 126, Folder 1472)
      - Correspondence, re. Relationship between World University Services and International University Service including Herluf Jensen's statement to WUS General Assembly on behalf of the WSCF, 1956-1958 (Box 126, Folder 1473)
      - Hungarian student relief appeal, 1956 (Box 126, Folder 1474)
      - Minutes, International Student Services, World Student Relief, and World University Service, 1950-1951 (Box 126, Folder 1475)
      - Minutes, World University Service Executive Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 126, Folder 1476)
      - Minutes, World University Service Executive Committee, 1952-1955 (Box 126, Folder 1477)
      - Minutes, World University Service Executive Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 126, Folder 1478)
      - Miscellaneous, 1955, 1957 (Box 126, Folder 1479)
      - Nominations to the General Assembly, 1958 (Box 126, Folder 1480)
      - Program materials and notes by John Deschner from the annual conference in Norway, July 20-30, 1951 (Box 126, Folder 1481)
      - Reports re. relationship between International Union of Students and the World University Service, 1954-1955 (Box 126, Folder 1482)
    - World University Service New York Office
      - 30 Centers study analyzing student attitudes toward international understanding, 1952-1953 (Box 127, Folder 1484)
      - 30 Centers study analyzing student attitudes toward international understanding, 1953-1955 (Box 127, Folder 1485)
      - Correspondence, General, 1952-1955 (Box 127, Folder 1486)
      - Correspondence, General, 1955 (Box 127, Folder 1487)
      - Correspondence, re. Harvard-Delhi mutual service program, 1955-1956 (Box 127, Folder 1488)
      - Correspondence, General, 1956-1958 (Box 127, Folder 1489)
      - Correspondence, USCC appointments to WUS committees, 1957-1958 (Box 127, Folder 1490)
      - Correspondence, re. African Medical Scholarship Trust Fund, 1957-1958 (Box 127, Folder 1491)
      - Finance information, 1955-1957 (Box 127, Folder 1492)
      - Memos, General Committee, 1956-1959 (Box 127, Folder 1493)
      - Minutes, Annual meeting of the General Committee, 1952-1958 (Box 127, Folder 1494)
      - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1952-1958 (Box 128, Folder 1495)
      - Minutes, General Committee, 1952-1957 (Box 128, Folder 1496)
      - Minutes, National Consulting Committee, 1952-1955 (Box 128, Folder 1497)
      - Reports, World University Service workshop held in connection with the current WUS study of education for international understanding in the extra-curriculum at American colleges (30 Center study), 1954 (Box 128, Folder 1498)
      - Reports, World University Service--International Union of Students analysis from regional and sponsoring agencies, 1955 (Box 128, Folder 1499)
      - Reports, re. Projects held in other countries, 1956 (Box 128, Folder 1500)
      - World University Service special appeals, 1955-1956 (Box 128, Folder 1501)
    - Publications and Printed Materials
      - Booklets, Humanities and University Education: a Report on Symposium Sessions During the General Assembly Held at Mysore, India and The University's Role in the Meeting of Orient and Occident: a Symposium Held as Part of the WUS General Assembly, Nijenrode, Netherlands, 1956, 1957 (Box 128, Folder 1502)
      - Booklets, WUS in Southeast Asia: a Report on Visits to Southeast Asian WUS Committees by Rafe-Uz-Zaman, August 27, 1956-January 31, 1957 (Box 128, Folder 1503)
      - Brochures, flyers, and leaflets, 1954-1958 (Box 129, Folder 1504)
      - Minutes of the General Assembly of World University Service, 1951, 1955-1957 (Box 129, Folder 1505)
      - Newsletter and news release, WUS News and news releases from World University Service, 1954-1956, 1958 (Box 129, Folder 1506)
      - Periodicals, Université 47: I.S.S. Bulletin and WUS in Action, March 1947, 1956, October 1958 (Box 129, Folder 1507)
      - Pamphlets, World Student Relief 1940-1950, and World University Service: a report, an appeal, 1950, 1953, 1955 (Box 129, Folder 1508)
      - Pamphlets, Programme of Action, 1952-1956 (Box 129, Folder 1509)
      - Reports, Annual Report of International Student Service 1946-1947 and annual reports of WUS, 1947, 1952-1954, 1957 (Box 129, Folder 1510)
      - Reports, Problems of Student Health in Southeast Asia: a Report of an Experts Conference and WUS Annual International Conference, 1951 (Box 129, Folder 1511)
  - Other Organizations
    - American Council on African Education, 1945 (Box 153, Folder 1760)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 153, Folder 1761)
    - American Youth for a Free World, 1947-1948 (Box 153, Folder 1762)
    - Brochures from miscellaneous organizationa, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 1763)
    - Carnegie projects, 1949 (Box 153, Folder 1764)
    - Children to Palestine, 1949 (Box 153, Folder 1765)
    - Church Committee on Overseas Relief and Reconstruction: Elsie Thomas Culver's trip to Europe (Box 153, Folder 1766)
    - Church World Service, 1947, 1949 (Box 153, Folder 1767)
    - Committee for a Christian University in Japan, 1948-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1768)
    - Federal Council of Churches, 1946-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1769)
    - Federal Council of Churches, Commission of the Ministry, 1949 (Box 154, Folder 1770)
    - Fellowship of Southern Churchmen, 1949 (Box 154, Folder 1771)
    - Foreign Missions Conference, 1948 (Box 154, Folder 1772)
    - Golden Rule Foundation, 1950 (Box 154, Folder 1773)
    - Haddam House, 1948-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1774)
    - Interim Committee for National Coordinating Council of Young Adult Organizations, 1946-1947 (Box 154, Folder 1775)
    - International Studey Tour Alliance, 1950 (Box 154, Folder 1776)
    - International Union of Students, 1946-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1777)
    - Inter-Varsity Christian Fellowship, 1948-1951 (Box 154, Folder 1778)
    - Mennonite Youth Fellowship, 1949 (Box 154, Folder 1779)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, 1945-1947 (Box 154, Folder 1780)
    - Missionary Education Movement, 1946, 1949 (Box 154, Folder 1781)
    - NAACP, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 1782)
    - National Association of College University Chaplains, 1948-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1783)
    - National Baptist Student Union, 1957-1959 (Box 154, Folder 1784)
    - National Commission on Church Study Work, 1949 (Box 154, Folder 1785)
    - National Continuations Committee of the Chicago Student Conference, 1946 (Box 154, Folder 1786)
    - National Coordinating Councilc of the Young Adult Organizations, 1946-1947 (Box 154, Folder 1787)
    - National Protestant Council on Higher Education, 1948, 1950 (Box 155, Folder 1788)
    - National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students, 1949 (Box 155, Folder 1789)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, 1947 (Box 155, Folder 1790)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, Young Adult Council, 1949 (Box 155, Folder 1791)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, Young Adult Council, 1951 (Box 155, Folder #1792)
    - National Stewardshiop Institute, 1949 (Box 155, Folder 1793)
    - National Student Association, 1948-1949 (Box 155, Folder 1794)
    - Newman Club Federation, 1948 (Box 155, Folder 1795)
    - Pan Orthodox Christian Movement, 1949-1952 (Box 155, Folder 1796)
    - Pressure Groups/Political Organizations, 1948-1949 (Box 155, Folder 1797)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Baptist Student: a Christian Collegiate Magazine, 1955-1956 (Box 155, Folder 1798)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Baptist Student: a Christian Collegiate Magazine, 1957-1958 (Box 155, Folder 1799)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, Brochures and pamphlets including Study Guide: The Christian Student in the World Crisis and Christian Ideals for Courtship and Marriage, 1948-1956 (Box 155, Folder 1800)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, Correspondence, 1947-1958 (Box 155, Folder 1801)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, Handbook for Baptist Student Union members (Box 156, Folder 1802)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Key News, 1956-1957 (Box 156, Folder 1803)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Key News, 1958-1959 (Box 156, Folder 1804)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, Miscellaneous newsletters, 1947-1957 (Box 156, Folder 1805)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Reveille: a Journal of Baptist Student Life and Reveille, Jr., 1949-1952 (Box 156, Folder 1806)
    - Southern Baptist Convention, The Signal: South Carolina BSU Paper, 1948-1950 (Box 156, Folder 1807)
    - Student Christian Movement, Middle Atlantic States, 1949, 1953 (Box 156, Folder 1808)
    - Student Christian Movement, New England, 1946-1949, 1952 (Box 156, Folder 1809)
    - Student Christian Movement, New England, 1958 (Box 157, Folder 1810)
    - Student Christian Movement, New York State includes group photograph, 1944-1949 (Box 157, Folder 1811)
    - Student Christian Movement, New York State, 1957-1959 (Box 157, Folder 1812)
    - Student Christian Union of Cleveland, Ohio, 1958-1959 (Box 157, Folder 1813)
    - United Christian Youth Movement, Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 157, Folder 1814)
    - UCYM, Correspondence re. Regional conferences, 1947 (Box 157, Folder 1815)
    - UCYM, Interdenominational Commission on Youth Service Projects, 1948-1949 (Box 157, Folder 1816)
    - UCYM, Publications including UCYM News, 1946-1949 (Box 157, Folder 1817)
    - UCYM, Report on World Council of Christian Education Conference, 1950 (Box 157, Folder 1818)
    - United Nations, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 1819)
    - UNESCO, 1946-1947 (Box 157, Folder 1820)
    - United World Federalists, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 1821)
    - World Affairs Council of Philadelphia, 1950 (Box 157, Folder 1822)
    - World Christian Youth Commission, 1949-1954 (Box 157, Folder 1823)
    - World Council of Christian Education, 1948-1949 (Box 158, Folder 1824)
    - World Council of Churches, Amsterdam Assembly, 1949 (Box 158, Folder 1825)
    - WCC, Correspondence, 1946, 1948-1949 (Box 158, Folder 1826)
    - WCC, Ecumenical Institute, 1947-1949 (Box 158, Folder 1827)
    - WCC, Meeting American Students by Bengt Hoffman, 1953 (Box 158, Folder 1828)
    - WCC, Pentecost materials, 1952 (Box 158, Folder 1829)
    - WCC, Publications, 1946-1946 (Box 158, Folder 1830)
    - WCC, Study Department, 1951-1952 (Box 158, Folder 1831)
    - WCC, Youth Department, 1948-1949 (Box 158, Folder 1832)
    - World Federation of Democratic Youth, 1946-1948 (Box 158, Folder 1833)
    - World Federation of Democratic Youth, World Youth Festival, 1947 (Box 158, Folder 1834)
    - Yale University, Publications including Christian Adventure at Yale: Dwight Hall Seventy-Fifth Anniversary by Kenneth Scott Latourette, 1956 (Box 158, Folder 1835)